Tamás Szirbucz - Freelance Software Engineer



I started my career as Software Engineer in 2008. I gained experience in several fields: embedded systems, compilers, IT security and web applications. In the past few years I worked as a Lead Java Engineer, where I had the chance to improve my management and leadership skille.

I'm a freak of code quality and performance, therefore I always take care about testing and measurement, since what is not measured, can not be controlled.

szirbucz.tamas@gmail.com







Expertise

Java Spring Framework Spring Data Spring Security JPA JUnit TDD MySQL MongoDB Pitest Hazelcast Kafka

ReactJS (AngularJS) (Selenium) (Performance optimization) (GDPR) (Clean Code) (Object Oriented Design) (Architecture Design

Continous Deployment HTML5 CSS3 Agile Kanban

Work Experience

Kode Konveyor OÜ - Lead Software Engineer (2019-04-16 -)

Working out a new software development process to be able to involve remote workers with minor development experience into projects.

- o Worked out the design rules for Java and React projects
- o Built up CI pipelines with full testing pyramid, static analysis and mutation testing
- Created education materials about basics of Java in TDD
- Mentoring remote colleagues (mainly from India)
- Working in a fully virtual team (5 members from 4 time zones)

EPAM Systems - Lead Software Engineer (2016-05-02 - 2018-10-31)

I led the development of a performance review tool with Java Spring based back-end and AngularJS based front-end. We used Kanban methodology and continous deployment with Unit-, Integration-, E2E- and manual tests, static analysis, code coverage, style check and code review in its pipeline. We worked in cooperation with remote QA team and management.

- · Massive performance improvement
- GDPR compliance
- o Extend CD pipeline with Unit test coverage
- Introduced Apache Kafka and moved all external APIs to it
- $\circ~$ Change JSP parts to Angular front-end

Balasys IT Security Kft - Software Engineer (2014-09-01 - 2016-04-29)

Application layer proxy firewall

- Improvement of the user interface (GTK)
- Extended in-house build tool with useful features
- o Found a "wrong size of NULL" bug in a Linux kernel lib
- Worked on Content Vectoring interface.

Hightec EDV-Systeme GmbH - Software Engineer (2013-09-01 - 2014-07-31)

Development of GCC compiler backends for several embedded architectures.

- o Implement XML export of linker map and objdump
- Introduced instruction set of new CPU version into our assembler
- $\circ \ \ \, \text{Developed compile time optimizations}$

Hightec Hungary Kft - Software Engineer (2011-03-01 - 2013-08-30)

Development of GCC compiler backends for several embedded architectures.

- Introduced support of new CPU vendor
- Actively participated in the ISO-26262 audit of the compiler

Department of Software Engineering, University of Szeged - Software Engineer (2008-05-05 - 2011-02-28)

Implement Procedural Abstraction compiler optimization

o 10-20% less binary size on popular open source projects.

Multifloor blueprint display integration with Open Street Maps

- C# & ASP.Net administration module for add and set position of blueprints
- Extended JS Map tool with controller for changing floors

Development of Webkit browser engine

- JIT optimizations
- Performance measurement

Sensor network for check state of floodlight

- Kernel module for own sensor HW
- $\circ~$ Bash scripts to collect sensor data from several nodes into one XML $\,$

Education & Training

Program Designer Mathematician, Master - University of Szeged (2005-2011)

- Java, C/C++, C#, HTML, CSS, XML
- Databases (SQL, PL/SQL, normalization)
- Software Engineering Processes
- Formal Languages and Automata
- Artificial Intelligence
- Image Processing

Doctoral School of Computer Science, PhD - University of Szeged (2011-2014)[unfinished]

- Software MetricsReverse Engineering
- Refactoring
- Machine Learning
- Natural Language Processing
- Teaching experience:
 - Programming Languages (Smalltalk, Haskell, Prolog, Occam)
 Basics of Programming (C)
 Operating Systems (Bash & Bat scripting)

 - Parallel Programming (Java concurrency, Occam, PVM)

Java Academy - EPAM Systems (2016)

- Java fundamentals
- Spring Framework / MVC / Data / Security
- Hibernate, JPA, SQL
- OOP Design Patterns and Principles
- Web Application Development
 Building Web Services
 Unit testing, Mocking, TDD

- Clean Code
- Agile Methodologies
- Front-End technologies
- Version Control and CI

Introduction to Management - EPAM Systems (2017)

- Leadership and Team Building
- Motivation
- Time Management
- Negotiation
- Project and Delivery Management

Powered by https://github.com/szirbucz/cv